{
	"question_set_id": "a34acaa5-d40a-4339-9264-121e74258139",
	"topic_id": "806e2b8d-2d16-4138-abab-507ce429eacf",
	"tags": ["the-aircraft", "maintenance"],
	"title": "The Aircraft",
	"references": [
		{
			"text": "Waypoints Vol 05: PPL/CPL Air Law. Chapter 2: The Aircraft",
			"url": "https://www.waypoints.nz/products/vol-05-ppl-cpl-air-law-january-2017"
		}
	],
	"questions": [
    {
			"question": "The __________ of an aircraft must ensure that the aircraft is maintained in an airworthy condition.",
			"answer": "Operator.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "With regard to maintenance, what does AD stand for and how does it relate to aircraft airworthiness?",
			"answer": "Airworthiness Directive. All applicable ADs must be complied with",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "All defects must be rectified before flight, except for which instruments and equipment?",
			"answer": "Any permitted to be inoperative under part 91.537 (either by MEL, or aircraft under 5700kg and meeting the other conditions of 91.537, or with a special flight permit).",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.537 - Inoperative instruments and equipment)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "The aircraft must be maintained under a Maintenance Programme approved under: Part 119 (specifically for ___ __________), or Part 91 (specifically for aircraft issued with a __________/__________ airworthiness certificate), or under the __________ maintenance schedule.",
			"answer": "Air Operations. Special/experimental. Manufacturer's.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.607 - Approval of maintenance programmes)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "The aircraft must be inspected in conformity with Part ___, or the __________ __________ __________ (OMM), or in conformity with another approved maintenance programme.",
			"answer": "91. Operator's Maintenance Manual.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "An inspection must be performed every ___ months, or ___ hours, whichever comes __________. What is the exception to this?",
			"answer": "12. 100. If the aircraft is maintained under a maintenance schedule which doesn't require an annual or 100 hour inspection.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "How often (at least) must the following systems be inspected? Radios, (for operations under IFR): ___ months, static pressure and altimeter systems: ___ months, transponders: ___ months, ELTs: ___ months or ___ hours, whichever is __________.",
			"answer": "24 months. 24 months. 24 months. 12 months. 100 hours. Sooner.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.605(e) - Maintenance programmes and schedules)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "How often must a Review of Airworthiness be carried out?",
			"answer": "Within the preceeding 12 months, or within the preceding 24 months for an aircraft not operated for hire or reward.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.615 - Review of Airworthiness)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "How often must a Maintenance Review be carried out. Maintenance review requirements are in CAR Part ___.",
			"answer": "Within the preceeding 12 months. 135.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 135 (135.415 - Maintenance Review)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_135_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Instruments or equipment permitted to be inoperative must be __________ and details recorded in the __________ __________ __________.",
			"answer": "Placarded. Aircraft technical log.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-5",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 91 (91.603 - General Maintenance Requirements)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_091_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		}
	]
}
